hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft we are
starting here at the elytra course
because I was really hoping that there'd
be a few more diamonds in here but
nothing unfortunately since the last
time so to give you guys a bit of an
update last episode literally all of my
diamonds over four stacks of them
vanished from my ender chest and I'm
down to just two diamonds that's like
having two pennies to rub together in
this game everything's expensive I'm not
sure what's happened apparently there's
absolutely nothing wrong with my Ender
Chest so there's a chance maybe I just
left them somewhere and took them out
and I don't know I've really I've looked
everywhere I cannot find them but I'm
not gonna worry about it there's always
ways to get diamonds back but this is a
little bit annoying it's a little bit
frustrating my diamonds are missing but
as I was flying around the hermitcraft
server as I normally do yeah I saw this
thing and I've asked several Hermits
what this is is and none of them seem to
know it looks really suspicious I think
that's probably about the most
suspicious thing I've ever seen floating
around apart from the giant cookie so I
thought maybe it wouldn't hurt at the
start of this episode to take a look
inside there's no there's nothing in the
blast furnaces there's just there's just
Redstone components I was really
expecting this to blow up I don't know
what it is but I was expecting it to
just blow up maybe this is something to
do with cherry and it's like a
advertising campaign I really don't know
well that was uneventful I was expecting
it to probably explode because I mean
like I said it looks very suspicious so
that was really nothing in the end
however there is something very exciting
that I want to show you all and it is
this what is that it is a poisonous
potato and this is going to be
the worst thing
that a Hermit can come across why
because I am inventing a brand new game
that's right tag is almost coming back
so the tag game ended a long time ago
because the Hermits got sick of it so
I'm making a new one and it's all to do
with this poisonous potato and here is
how it works this is the Hot Potato
and the idea is to get this item into
somebody else's inventory without them
knowing but here's the twist you can
rename the Hot Potato to include a
punishment for example give green 10
diamonds so I find someone AFK I drop
the potato in their inventory and I
leave
they then find the potato and they see
it in their inventory and it says give
green 10 diamonds they've then been
given the hot potato and they have to do
what it says no matter what it says so
they give me the diamonds and I make a
profit and I run away but here's the
catch if they catch me giving them the
potato or trying to sneak it in
then the punishment backfires and I have
to give them 10 diamonds so it is a risk
reward game you have to choose your
targets carefully and sneak this potato
into their inventory with a punishment
so my first one isn't actually going to
be give green 10 diamonds I'm gonna do
something maybe a little bit more
strange so one of the problems is that
there's not a lot of space on this so
I'm just gonna change it to HP which
means hot potato
record your intro in different length in
diff Lang so you've kind of got to use
some text speech here
so this says this is the Hot Potato you
have to record your intro in your next
episode in a different language I don't
really mind what the language is but I'm
gonna choose someone that isn't already
speaking two languages so someone that
probably speaks just English and watch
them as they have to do their entire
introduction to like the first 10
seconds I'll clarify with whoever we get
they've got to record the thing in a
different language and of course if it
fails I have to record my intro in a
different language so I wouldn't want to
do that as a pretty difficult thing to
do it's it'll be fun to laugh at them so
now we just have to find someone to
pertate there's actually no one online
right now so I think the best thing we
can do is head over to hermitville and
see what's occurring over there but
we're gonna keep this potato on us until
we get an opportunity so I haven't
actually had a look yet what Randomness
and extreme things are we going to find
in hermitville today
um oh well Bren Bob's vacated the
building that's awesome so it looks like
he's now gone he's just vamoosed but the
the stream you know for for a hippie
that's all about the environment he's
left a lot of CO2 around I think this is
probably gonna stick around for a long
time but at least a mark of his efforts
were there the dragon is covered oh whoa
whoa this wasn't there before the
dragons covered in snow it's
yeah that's kind of uh taken away some
of the oomph of the Dragon
so it looks like scars giant plant now
has a giant thunderstorm around it he's
playing with fire is he above me and oh
hold on hold on
mumbo's now decided to give up
there's a giant white flag of surrender
so I wondered what Mumbo was gonna do
because he hasn't done anything since
the rocket took off
so he's just decided to give up but at
the same time in very contradictory
fashion
it looks like it's actually the tallest
thing is it the build height here no
it's not it's definitely not up to build
height so build off is not over quite
yet
so oh my goodness we've got a giant
thunderstorm with a couple of flowers
out there at the top of it I'm not
really sure what that's supposed to do
but it is definitely higher than my
dragon and this white flag is above my
dragon and iskal is currently in last
place but that leaves the question what
do I do
I can't defeat a cloud with a ball of
fire
um
I thought the dragon would scare
everyone off well it clearly scared
Mumbo into giving up but I need to think
of a way to build my house
a little bit taller you know maybe I
could just build out here and just go
around the side and end up out the back
there but I think honestly this is one
of my favorite things that's happened on
hermitcraft the build offers uh it's
just amazing it's it surprisingly it
looks very clean it's got a well this is
just it's just so cool it looks like one
of my build swap episodes that's what
this looks like except much better and
bigger so anyway let's build the house
up a little bit taller and maybe even
get this Dragon to fire something at
scar you know knock off the top of this
hat or something we need to scare him
anyway so let's do it wait wait wait
wait wait wait wait wait actually before
we do that I logged in the very next day
I was about to go and do the work to the
base and this is there look look at this
I I can't leave this place for more than
two minutes
let's go and take a look because this
changes my entire game plan so scar has
got a giant cannon on a castle on top of
the cloud so that's why the cloud was
there
and he's built up all the way to to
build limit two five five isn't that
build height
oh no
he's nobody tells scar that he's one
short nobody tell him he's one shot okay
he probably doesn't know I I think the
only way to deal with this
is a fireball I was wondering like a
fireball wouldn't do much to a cloud but
it sure is oh wait so he's got a
cannonball there well I think we can
fire a fire a fireball and knock that
Cannon way out of place at the same time
all right so Scar's busy doing that
let's start the time lapse
and let's get this Fireball on the road
shall we we've got a lot of work to do
so we might as well start now
so this is the scene as it currently
stands scar is on top of a cloud firing
a cannon at my dragon and iskal is
lagging behind a little bit but Mumbo
has built the White Flag above mine look
how beautiful this looks but we have got
a lot of work to do so let's take this
in as it stands and then crack on with
what we're going to be doing with our
build basically I want to make the house
bigger but I don't want to interrupt the
build that I've already got the dragon
I'd really just don't want to touch it
it's amazing I don't want anything bad
to happen to this precious little angel
so I built the house around the dragon
it literally curves right round and goes
straight up where it was above mumbo's
flag and above scars build so we're back
on top ladies and gentlemen but we need
to then go ahead and decorate all of it
add the windows and stuff to be honest
with you that bit's just now a chore all
but I like the way that it curves around
the dragon it doesn't interrupt it the
the wing is around everything and that
was the main thing but since scar fired
the first bullet mine my dragon was
defensive and then he's gone on the
offensive so now we are going to give
him a taste of his own medicine then
we're going to send a fireball straight
at him now I hate working with stained
glass I think it's my least favorite
thing and I haven't got much experience
doing it I've really kind of suck at
doing this sort of thing so this was a
bit of a first for me I'd never made any
sort of Fireball using stained glass or
anything like that the most I've ever
done is a bit of smoke so I think all in
all I did a pretty good job even though
it definitely isn't the best but the
fireball knocked the cannon off course
which then went straight through mumbo's
white flag of surrender this is a kind
of a no Mumbo you don't get to win and
give up at the same time so the
Cannonball has gone straight off course
straight away from the dragon where it
was going and the fireball is heading
straight for Scar's face or Cannon
wherever it's going I think this looks
really cool and this is exactly why we
have a dragon on top of our base so that
we can defend from attacks like that so
all in all I think we made a pretty good
move it looks like I got the angles
slightly wrong
the mouth is down here but the fireball
is a little bit higher so I may have
messed that up but we'll just pretend
that the dragon raised its head to fire
the Fireball and that's totally normal
what's not normal is the giant dabbing
penguin
since I did this time lapse and we
knocked scars cannonball into mumbo's
white flag
iskal has built a dabbing Penguin on top
of an iceberg which is on top of his
space station which is on top of the
Moon which is on top of a magnet which
is on top of the Eiffel Tower what is
going on
at least I've been fairly consistent
with mine
so it officially looks like all of us
with the exception of Mumbo who has
officially retired from the game and
this is why we've put this cannibal
straight through his flag to show that
he is he is officially surrendered even
though he did get back on top very
briefly the three of us iskau and myself
are all at the same level meaning that's
pretty much the end of the build off
or is it I think what we're going to
have to do is get together with iskow
and Scar in The Next Episode to work out
who officially has won the build off
but can we just please appreciate quite
how insane this is and how beautiful it
is I don't think anything like this will
ever happen again by accident on the
hermitcraft server it's absolutely
incredible and it's incredibly fun to
fly around in as well because of all the
different laser beams and stuff that are
going on possibly one of my favorite
things that's happened this season
however
if we press tab for just two seconds we
can see two people online XI Zuma void
and Mumbo jumbolio who is officially AFK
so I think we know
who our Target is and I was hoping it
was gonna be Mumbo who our Target is for
the Hot Potato I've still got it on me
hot potato record your intro in a
different language I can't think of
anyone better who would have a hard time
saying their introduction in another
language the mumbo jumbo unless he's
hiding a second language skill from us I
think this could be very very funny now
seeing as he's AFK I'm guessing he's in
his farming area which is why I'm
heading over there through the nether
here we are in his farming area seeing
as that is the only Farm online I'm
guessing he's somewhere up there I can't
actually see him is that on yep there it
goes and what is in here
oh mumbo jumbo plans he's got a little
table here concrete maker iron farm
villager breeder zero tick sugarcane oh
this is just his farm maybe we should
add our own in here farm that gives
green lots of diamonds that seems like a
really good plan to add to that list so
as long as he follows his own plan we
should be fine so where is he if he's
not in there he's not in the control
room
and he's not there
is that him
yeah there we go oh his head's on
backwards
mumbo jumbo
when are you gonna learn not to go AFK
so this is actually the first time that
anyone's gonna get potatoed
so hopefully he hasn't got a full
inventory because if he's got a full
inventory this doesn't work ah there we
go there's all his stuff I have just
broken a bit of glass here so wow he's
got loads of diamonds he just carries
diamonds on him this is a really big
insight into what mumbo jumbo carries
around he carries rounds a stack and a
half of diamonds and some leather
trousers
that's really weird
that's really really weird Okay so we've
got the potato as long as this goes into
his inventory
which it should
pop
and he hasn't noticed us because he's
AFK
we're pretty much in the clear so I'm so
confident that he's going to be AFK for
a long time I'm pretty sure that counts
as not being noticed so what we're going
to do is we're going to write down to
explain the game because mumbo jumbo
probably won't have seen the rules and
everything so I'm just going to explain
to him what's going on wow I was writing
this book for so long that it's now
night time okay so here we go hi Mumbo
you have been potatoed that means you
have had the Hot Potato thrown in your
inventory Without You noticing you guys
already know this but I'm just gonna
read it out anyway this is a new game
invented by me the green Menace since
you have the Hot Potato you must do the
punishment on it and your punishment is
in the next episode you must do your
introduction in another language
approximately 10 to 20 seconds remember
these are very loose rules so if he if
he just does like the hello my name is
Mumbo and welcome back to another
hermitcraft episode that's fine as long
as he does that in another in another
language I'll be happy you could choose
any language you want now now you must
get rid of the Hot Potato to do this you
must sneak it into someone's inventory
without them noticing
here's the twist you can write your own
punishment on the potato for the hermit
to do for example give me 10 diamonds we
went over this however if you are caught
in the moment of potatoing someone the
punishment will backfire and you must
perform the punishment and start over if
you fail you must make a new punishment
and find a new Target this game is
really simple I promise and I want to
keep it simple I don't want there to be
too many rules so good luck you can
Target any hermit even the person who
got you get creative but be prepared for
it to all go wrong so I want to keep the
rules as minimal as possible so
hopefully this all makes sense now this
book here is just to be handed out
because it can be difficult to know
exactly what's going on with a brand new
game so this isn't a rule book just so
unclear this isn't a rule book this is
just to explain to Mumbo who might not
know what's going on there we go wait
yep I heard that pop that means he's got
it Mission successful the first potato
Wing has been done and well it was
pretty easy but imagine how crazy this
game's going to become when people start
baiting each other to get potatoed when
people start filling their inventory
with random junk so that they're
protected it's gonna the tactics in this
are gonna be quite insane
so we made a brand new tag game and the
build off is starting to come to a
conclusion that means we need to find
something else to do please leave a
comment down below if you have any ideas
for what we should be doing on
hermitcraft next however there is one
last thing that I want to do before we
call this episode done because X has
informed me that he is split the elytra
course into two normal mode which is GRE
and fun electricals thanks for that and
reverse mode so he took two minutes 47
plus eight penalties so it took him two
minutes 55 to do it in reverse so that
means the full elytra course but
backwards
I think we're gonna have to try and set
a better score than this because we're
at the top here even though I managed to
get the same as the exact same score
twice and we've got 15 uh you know what
it's not such a big deal that we lost
our diamonds because we're getting them
back 17 diamonds at least means I
haven't got none left actually this is a
really big deal because it means I can
officially sign up for iskal's mini game
which I wasn't able to do before because
I've not got any diamonds you know I
should really just go mining but it's
just kind of boring at this point right
there we go signing up uh I should write
the paper down I'll be honest I don't
really know what I'm signing up for I
was elected to lead not to read
all right so let's go and do this elytra
course backwards and see if we can beat
XI
Zuma's score three two one go we even
got the ding to set us off so so we're
going backwards I know the course inside
and out so this shouldn't be too
difficult as long as the world will load
around us in time
so this is where I always end up getting
hit come on
Yes we made that through if I can get a
no hit run on this I will set the best
score obviously I won't know what the
score is until the editing process now
this is going to be a tricky one
ah I just have to guess oh it's not
loading in
I have to guess
this is ten times harder
when the world doesn't load in
I literally have to slow myself down
because it won't load in
the goal is just to beat X's score I
will probably have to redo this look at
this how am I supposed to do my lecture
course at speed if I can't even see the
elytra course
through this hoop down here
Ah that's another hit up
down through the bamboo forest in
Concord oh this is weird doing it this
way
I have to ah I have to know where my
course is just blindly
through here through the quitter tube
which is over here through the grass no
the leaves we're doing well
and through this one which is
particularly difficult go down ah no we
hit the floor we hit the floor
oh this is a terrible run this is a
terrible run but I have a feeling it
might still be better than X's
through here through the ice ow that's
three hits
down
Come on load in
I can't see it come on come on
come on
oh this is terrible
and under
up
oh you're kidding me well that that is
it that is
four hits that was a really awful awful
run because the world would not load in
and it made it pretty much impossible to
do that at speed however I will write
down the time when I know obviously it's
you guys know what it is look
but I'm definitely gonna do that again
at some point maybe when there's not two
people AFK at a farm somewhere because
the server is unbelievably laggy anyway
that's it for today's episode I hope you
enjoyed thank you very much for watching
as always and I can't wait to see Ella
Mumbo and do his uh do his next
introduction in another language
although remember next episode he will
be reading the book so it might be the
episode after that he does the intro I
don't know how he's gonna do it either
one is fine I don't really I don't
really mind but maybe he will read the
potato first in his next episode and
then the punishment will be the episode
after either way we all get our
introduction in another language I
wonder what language he's gonna choose I
hope he chooses a good one anyway thank
you very much for watching and good bye